Previously on
Space Brothers
むった
＜不運に縁がある 兄･六太は➡
Older brother Mutta is plagued by bad luck.
数々の困難をなんとかくぐり抜け
月ミッションへの➡
Having overcome multiple obstacles, he's a step closer to a lunar mission.
新たな一歩を
踏み出そうとしている＞
Meanwhile, younger brother Hibito becomes the first Japanese moonwalker, but he has an accident and nearly dies.
＜一方 日本人初の
ひびと
ﾑｰﾝｳｫｰｶｰとなった日々人は➡
月面で事故に遭い
死の瀬戸際まで追いつめられる＞
＜地球に帰還したものの
事故の影響は➡
After returning to Earth, he discovers the accident has left him traumatized.
心の奥深くに刻み込まれていた＞
＜このままでは船外活動ができず
月ミッションには加われない＞
As things stand, since he cannot participate in EVA, he's barred from lunar missions.
＜日々人は この事実を
兄･六太にも伏せたまま➡
Hibito keeps this information a secret from his
brother, as he heads to chilly Russia to recover.
かつての自分を取り戻すべく
極寒の地･ロシアへと向かった＞
なんば
(南波六太)５秒前…
４･３･２･１｡
T-5!
4!
3!
2!
1!
バーティカル･クライムロール！
レッツゴー!!
Vertical climb roll...
Let's go!
＜私はどうしても月に行きたい＞
I must reach the moon.
＜月への道を開くため➡
To express my passion,
強い思いを示すため
私は魔法の裏技➡
I performed a magic trick, the vertical climb roll, for Chief Butler.
バーティカル･クライムロールを
バトラー室長に披露し…＞
Okay! Time for the next one!
さぁ～次 行くぞ～！
ハートマーク レッツゴー！
Heart in the sky...
Let's go!
＜せりかさんのために作った
ハートマークを➡
While Serika was busy mistaking my heart for an Alien Baltan...
見事にバルタン星人と
勘違いされていた頃…＞
《もう…ダメなんだ…｡➡
It's over...
もう できないんだ…》
I can no longer do any of the things I once could...
＜シャロンの病状は
ますます悪化していた…＞
Sharon's condition continued to worsen.
Yeah, they only have sixty days of sunlight a year here.
(南波日々人)ああ ３６５日中➡
晴れんのは６０日くらいだね｡
それ以外は 曇り｡
[ｹｲﾀｲ](南波母)ウソだぁ～！
Every other day is cloudy.
You're lying!
I'm not.
ウソじゃないよ
１０月から４月は雪｡
It snows from October to April.
ロシアには
季節が２つしかないね｡
Russia only has two seasons.
何と何だと思う？
[ｹｲﾀｲ](母)えっ 何？何？教えて！
Guess which two.
Eh? Which ones? Tell me!
考える気 ゼロだな
母ちゃん｡
You aren't even going to try, Mom?
｢寒い冬｣と｢寒くない冬｣だ｡
Winters that are cold and winters that aren't.
[ｹｲﾀｲ](母)へぇ～！今どっち？
Oh...
Which is it now?
Uh... I can't tell.
多分 ギリギリ寒くない冬
寒いけど…｡
Probably it's the winter that isn't cold.
But it's still cold.
どうしたの？
オリガ｡
What's wrong, Olga?
(オリガ)ううん なあんもない｡
Oh, it's nothing.
Hey, don't start practicing in the middle of the street...
ちょっと こんなとこで
レッスン始めないでよ～｡
何？急に｡
What brought that on?
わかんないけど…飛んじゃった｡
I'm not sure.
I just felt like jumping.
Swayed by a profound sadness
My daydreams lay a bouquet at my feet
space brothers
I stand atop a brand new world
Hoping to catch whatever falls out of this unprecedented miracle
They're here yet again
The days I'll spend growing distant from you
I'll have miles to go before I sleep in peace
I can see the faint radiance of hope
It got mixed into your blood one day and hasn't let you go
That's all
My body grows nimbler by the day
And my heart's shedding tears because it can't keep up
But I lost something once I became an adult
My light slumber
I can see the faint radiance of hope
It's mixed into your blood, so I'll never let you go
That's all
My body stands atop a stage that it won't run away from even if it rains
That makes me break out into a sprint, so goodbye
My midnight slumbers
#76 Olga
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)オウ！ヒビチョフ！➡
Hey, Hibichov...
どうだ？この４日間
久しぶりのロシアには慣れたか？
Was four days enough to for you to get used to being back in Russia?
バッチリだよ
以前と何も変わってない｡
You bet...
Nothing's changed.
だから 早く訓練始めさせてよ｡
So let me start training, already.
｢１週間 何もすんな｣なんて
退屈で変になる｡
A week off is going to bore me to death.
その言い方じゃ
まだ慣れたとは言えないな｡
Sounds like you aren't used to being back yet.
本当に ロシア慣れした奴ならば
こう答える！
Here's what a Russian would say!
Huh?
聞いてくれよ 逆に！
Ask me the same question...
《めんどくせぇ…》
He's such a pain...
Well, are you used to being back in Russia, Ivan?
どうなの？イヴァン
ロシアには慣れた？
う～む よく分からんな｡
Hmm, not sure...
今 酔っ払ってるから
ハッハハハ…！
I'm too drunk.
わかったな ヒビチョフ
あと３日の辛抱だ｡
Okay, Hibichov?
You just have to wait three more days.
hibichov
《勝手に あだ名を…》
What's with that nickname?
hibichov
行くぞ イヴァン
ソユーズシミュレーションだ｡
Let's go, Ivan...
Time to hit the Soyuz simulator.
オウ｡
そうだ ヒビチョフ➡
Oh.
I know, Hibichov... You should come home with me.
今晩 ウチに来い
家族を紹介する｡
I'll introduce you to my family.
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)ハッハハハハ！
I brought you some vodka.
は～い ウォッカ ビールもあるよ｡
We also have beer.
妻のエミーリアだ
昔は美人だった｡
This is my wife, Emilia.
She used to be a beauty...
今は超美人｡
Now, I'm a super beauty.
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)こっちは弟のミハエル｡
(ﾐﾊｴﾙ)やあ｡
This is Mikhail, my younger brother.
Hey!
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)その横は 誰だ？
知らない奴もいる｡
I have no idea who the one next to him is.
Come on... It's your buddy Vladimir.
おいおい ダチの
ウラジミールだぜ｡
まあ ウォッカでも飲め
ヒビチョフ ギュッと｡
Have some vodka, Hibichov.
Chug it!
いや ビールにしとくよ｡
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)なんだと？
Nah, I'll stick to beer.
What's that?
You're violating the most fundamental principle of health.
健康主義ぶるなよ！
ビールなんてジュースだぞ｡
Drinking beer is like drinking juice!
どんだけ酒好きなんだよ｡
You really like your liquor, huh?
そんなだから
ＩＳＳロシアモジュールには➡
That's why people gossip about liquor hidden in the Russian ISS module.
酒瓶が隠してあるとか
ウワサになるんだよ｡
それはウワサではない 事実だ｡
That isn't gossip... It's the truth.
ハッハハハハ…！
心の健康のためには
ある程度の酒は必要なのだ｡
You need liquor to maintain your health.
I'm home.
ただいま～｡
あっ おかえり｡
Oh, welcome back.
帰ってきたな｡
誰？
Looks like she's home.
Who's that?
娘だ｡
My daughter.
挨拶しろ オリガ
こちらは宇宙飛行士仲間の➡
Say hello, Olga.
This is my fellow astronaut, Nanba Hibichov.
ナンバ･ヒビチョフさん｡
ヒビトです｡
It's Hibito!
ヒビ…｡
Hibi...
ふ～ん こんばんは｡
Hello.
こんばんは｡
She's pretty...
美人だね～あんたの娘とは
思えないよ｡ハタチくらい？
I find it hard to believe she's your daughter.
She's around twenty?
何を言うか
あれは まだ１５だ｡
What are you talking about?
She's fifteen.
Fifteen?!
１５!?あれで１５!?
She's fifteen?
She looks old—
ずいぶんフケ…お 大人っぽいね｡
Mature for her age.
大人ぶってやがるんだ
化粧まで覚えやがって｡
She's trying to act grown-up with all that makeup...
バヤイ…｡➡
Crazy...
バヤイよ ヒビットだ｡➡
This is crazy! It's Hibbit...
モノホンだ！
The real one!
I never imagined that the original for Mr. Hibbit would come to our house.
まさか ミスターヒビットの
モデルになった張本人が➡
ウチに来るなんて！
バヤイ！
Crazy...
街で見かけたヒビットヘアは
ただのファンじゃなくて…｡
So when I saw that person with the Hibbit hairstyle, it wasn't just a fan.
こっちへ来たお前と
初めて会った時 気づいたぜ｡➡
The second I saw you, after you arrived, I noticed it.
お前の目の奥には
怯えと不安があるってな｡
I see the fear and anxiety in your eyes.
つら
そんな シケッ面で何ができる｡
You won't make any progress with that sour look on your face.
宇宙飛行士の顔ではないぞ！
That isn't an astronaut's face.
My son's room is open.
息子の部屋が空いてる
今日はもう泊まっていけ｡
Stay the night.
シケッ面ね…｡
Sour look on my face, huh?
イエーイって言わないのね｡
You haven't said, "Yay," yet.
いつ言うの？そろそろ？
When will you say it?
Soon?
今 この状況が
イエーイって気分に見える？
Do I look like I'm in a "Yay" mood?
でも 何で知ってんの？それ｡
But how do you know about that?
日本のアニメ
こっちでもやってるから｡
We get Japanese anime here.
私は あんなガキのアニメ
興味ないけどね｡➡
Not that I'm interested in kiddie shows.
ナントカヒビ…
ナントカみたいな｡
There's the series named Hibi-something.
Mr. Hibbit?
ミスターヒビットな｡
ヒビナントカは
いつも元気っぽいキャラなのに➡
Hibi-something's always bursting with energy.
ヒビチョフは そうでもないのね｡
But you're different.
ヒビットは
な～んも考えてなさそうだけど➡
Hibbit doesn't seem to have any worries.
ヒビチョフは色々 考えてるんだよ
オリガはさ➡
But Hibichov has a lot on his mind.
Say, Olga...
オリガは将来 何になるの？
What do you want to be when you grow up?
ダンサー｡
A dancer.
Oh, wow!
おおっ！スゴイ！やらけぇ～！
You really can bend yourself!
うわっ 何それ！大丈夫？
Uh, what are you doing?
Are you okay?
う うわっ…もういいって！
That's enough! You're scaring me!
なんか怖いよ わかったって！
I get the idea!
アルセニー･パラノフスキー｡➡
Arseny Parnovski.
副操縦士 ミハイル･ドリトリー｡
Co-pilot Mikhail Dmitri!
セス
そして このＣＥＳ-７３
月面基地計画➡
And this CES-73 Moonbase mission
船長を務めるのは
ＩＳＳ長期滞在➡
will be commanded by the man with a record 848 days logged on the ISS.
８４８日の最長記録を持つ➡
ロシアの英雄
イヴァン･トルストイ！
The hero of Russia, Ivan Tolstoy!
ようこそ みなさん｡
Glad to see everyone here.
《えらい人気だな》
He's really popular.
我々は今までのＩＳＳとは異なる
新たな訓練を積んできた｡
We have been training for more than ISS missions alone.
このようなチャンスに恵まれ
光栄に思う｡➡
I feel honored to be given this opportunity.
All three of us have more than enough training for this mission.
３人とも訓練は十分にした｡➡
As mission commander, I hope to ensure our training is put to good use.
それを活かせるよう 船長として
責務を立派に果たしたい｡
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)では いよいよ
リハビリ訓練を始める｡➡
It's time to start your rehabilitation.
Are you ready, Hibichov?
準備はいいな ヒビチョフ｡
Yeah.
そいつはソコール｡
ただの与圧服だ｡気を楽にな｡
This is a Sokol suit.
It's just a pressure suit.
Relax.
ここから あのラインまで
歩くだけだ｡簡単だろ？
You only need to walk over to that line.
Easy, right?
《心配するな
ここは月じゃない…》
There's nothing to worry about...
I'm not on the moon.
And I'm not wearing an EVA suit...
《そして これは船外服じゃない》
《何もかもが
あの時とは違うんだ…》
This is a completely different situation.
Are you all right, Hibito?
《うむ…こいつは
思ったより重症だな…》
This is worse than I expected.
(ｲｳﾞｧﾝ)ヒビチョフ！
Hibichov...
乗れ｡またウチで
みんなとメシを食おう｡
Get in.
You should eat with us again.
悪いけど…
今日は なんかいいや｡
Sorry, but I'm not in the mood today.
ひとりになりたい気分だし｡
I want to be alone.
ヒビチョフ 待たれ｡
Hey, hey, hey, Hibichov... Wait up.
ひとりになるなと
私は言ってるんだ｡
My goal is ensure you aren't left alone.
(ｱﾅｳﾝｽ)第５モジュールで
火災発生！➡
Fire detected in Module 5.
Fire-suppression system is malfunctioning.
消火システム故障｡
爆発の恐れアリ｡
Possibility of explosion.
(ﾋﾋﾞｯﾄ)みんな！
それぞれの力を出し合おう｡
Everyone, it's time to combine our powers!
みんなの持ってるもの…➡
Use whatever you've got!
フレディドッグは
経験と統率力を｡➡
Freddy Dog can provide experience and leadership!
ダミアンホークは技術を｡➡
Damian Hawk provides technical expertise!
バディゴリラは その腕力を｡➡
Buddy Gorilla provides brawn!
レッサーリンダと
カレンキャットは 知識と保護を｡
Red Panda Linda and Karen Cat provide knowledge and support!
今こそ みんなの力が必要だ！
この場を頼む｡
It's time to unite!
I'll let you guys handle this!
Wait up, Hibito!
(ﾊﾞﾃﾞｨｺﾞﾘﾗ)ちょっと待て ヒビット！
Are you going to Module 5 alone?
ひとりで第５モジュールへ
行く気か!!キケン過ぎる！
It's too dangerous!
誰かが行って爆発を止めないと！
(ﾌﾚﾃﾞｨﾄﾞｯｸﾞ)だが…｡
Someone has to go and stop the place from exploding!
But...
行かせてくれ！
ボクが持ってるのは…➡
Let me do this!
All I can provide is courage and energy!
勇気と元気だけなんだ｡
Yay!
イエーイ！うおおお…!!
[TV]≪ヒ…ヒビット！≫
[TV]≪行くなぁ ヒビットー!!≫
H-Hibbit!
Don't go, Hibbit!
[TV]♬～
[TV]僕らの英雄 ミスターヒビット
Mr. Hibbit is our hero!
バヤイ｡
Crazy.
Man, Hibbit is crazy...
あ～ ヒビット！バヤイ…｡
｢ボクが持ってるのは
勇気と元気だけなんだ｣｡
"All I can provide is courage and energy."
That's his response?
そぉ～きたかぁ！
(ｴﾐｰﾘｱ)オリガ｡
Olga?
ヒビチョフさんが来たわよ｡
Hibichov is here.
ふ～ん じゃ 後で行く｡
I'll drop by later, then.
Crazy!
(ｵﾘｶﾞ)バヤイ…！
What's wrong?
《なんでだ…ヒューストンに
いた頃より ひどくなってる》
Since I left Houston, it's worsened.
あずま
《吾妻さんの言うとおり
ロシアに来れば➡
I thought Azuma was right when he said I'd improve with some time in Russia...
マシになれると
思ってたんだけどな…》
⦅しばらくはロシアに行って
気分を入れかえてこい 日々人⦆
Go to Russia for a change in scenery.
I've asked someone to look after you...
⦅お前の面倒を見てくれるよう
ある人に頼んである⦆
⦅イヴァン･トルストイ｡
ロシアの英雄だ⦆
Ivan Tolstoy, a Russian hero.
⦅ガハハハハハ！⦆
I thought I'd be able to recover in a different environment...
《環境を変えれば
俺も変われると思ってた…》
What's wrong? You haven't touched your beer.
なんだ 全く
飲んどらんではないか！
You're no fun, Hibichov!
つまらんぞ ヒビチョフ！
そ～言われてもね…｡
Whatever you say...
あ オリガは何飲む？
What do you want to drink, Olga?
なんか…お酒｡
Something with alcohol.
Huh?
Hmm? Alcohol?
《酒…？》
フゥ～｡
Wh-What's she up to?
《な…何をやっとるんだ
コイツは!?》
なんでワイングラスで
飲んでんの？ジュース｡
Why are you using a wine glass to drink juice?
いいじゃない 気分だけ…｡
Wh-Why not?
I want to know how it feels.
私 まだ１７よ｡
まだお酒飲めないし…｡
I'm only seventeen.
So I can't drink yet...
You're fifteen!
お前 １５だろが アホ！
No, I'm turning sixteen this year!
(ｵﾘｶﾞ)違うよ！今年で１６だよ!!
いいか オリガ｡酒はやめとけ｡
Listen to me, Olga.
No alcohol.
しばらくは
そのジュースで我慢しろ｡
Stick with juice for now.
俺もジュースにしようかな｡
I think I'll have juice, too.
ヒビチョフ～
お前は逆に飲んだ方が良い！
Hibichov, you need to get drunk.
なあ イヴァン｡
明日のリハビリ訓練だけど…➡
Hey, Ivan...
For my rehabilitation tomorrow,
would it be okay if I train with you operating Soyuz?
ソユーズのマニュアル操作訓練
とかに変えていい？
あ？どういうことだ？
Hmm? What for?
たぶん 明日も同じことになる｡
I'm guessing the same thing will happen tomorrow.
失敗の回数が
増えれば増えるほど…➡
It feels like every time I fail,
俺は 宇宙飛行士じゃ
なくなっていく気がする｡
I'm less of an astronaut.
全然ないじゃん 勇気と元気｡
You don't have any courage or energy.
いや 別に…｡
Huh?
Nothing, never mind.
悪いけど 今日は帰るよ｡
Sorry, but I need to get going.
あっ…おいおい 酒は？
Wait, your drink...
気分じゃないんだ｡またいつか｡
I'm not in the mood.
I'll come again.
The hasty hare and the slow and steady turtle
Are both headed toward the place they call their goals
We forgot something very important once we grew up
Forget tomorrow, what can I do right now?
But the two of us
Have always remembered
The importance of taking off
The heavy shackles of hesitation
A brand new world
Is always waiting one step ahead of us
Even our failures will give us strength
And that will be the start of a new world
Next time, on
#77 An Astronaut's Daughter
Space Brothers
Where'd he go?
＜どこに行きやがった あの野郎＞
＜与圧服を着ただけで➡
I can't even walk ten meters in a pressure suit...
たった１０メートルも
歩けなくなるなんて➡
What am I supposed to do?
どうしたらいい？＞
Next time, on Space Brothers:
"An Astronaut's Daughter"
Am I no longer qualified to be an astronaut?
＜俺は
宇宙飛行士 失格なんだろうな＞
Mr. Hibbit!
(ﾓｸﾞﾌｧｰ)はい 集合～｡
Okay, gather around!
We'll start your training with some running.
というわけで 最初の訓練は
ランニングよ！走るわよ！
私は走れないので
飛んでもいいか？
I can't run, so can I fly instead?
ダメよ！飛んだら
ランニングじゃないでしょ!!
No, that wouldn't count as running.
Does that mean I can't hop?
てことは 跳ねるのもダメ？
I told you to run!
走るっつってんでしょ！ハイ!!
Okay, everyone follow me.
みんな あたしの後についてきて！
Yay!
イエーイ！
飛びたい…｡
I want to fly.
(ﾓｸﾞﾌｧｰ)どうしてジョギングが
必要かわかる？➡
Do you know why jogging is important?
Naturally, it helps build muscle and stamina.
筋力･持久力を
鍛えることになるのは当然よね！
I'm not a good runner...
(ﾋﾋﾞｯﾄ)走りづらいよ～｡
ウホッ!?
(ﾚｯｻｰﾘﾝﾀﾞ)キャッ！
What are you doing?
ニャにすんのよ バカ～！
私はニオイで
モグファーの進む方向がわかる｡
My nose will tell me the direction Moleifer is headed.
Follow me.
私についてこい！鼻が利く私に｡
I have a sharp nose.
うわっ！うわぁ～!!
What are you all doing?
何やってんのよ あんたら！
モグファー じゃま！
You're not helping, Moleifer...
See you next week!